&gt;&gt; Good afternoon everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家下午好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
I hope everybody's having a
我希望这一次的 WWDC 大会
great WWDC so far and that some
能让每个人都获益匪浅
of you managed to go see Todd's
不久前你们当中有些人
talk just a little bit ago, he's
听过 Todd 的演讲
a great speaker and an
这位伙计不仅话讲得好
all-around awesome dude, so I
而且在各方面都很出色
hope you enjoyed that.
所以我希望大家能够喜欢他的演讲
My name is Skylar Peterson, I am
我叫 Skylar Peterson
a member of Apple's iOS
是苹果 iOS 辅助功能
Accessibility Team and I'm here
开发团队的一员  今天在这里我
today to talk to you about
要和大家分享
what's new in accessibility this
本年度 iOS 新增的
year.
辅助功能
So, for those of you that don't
如果有人不是很清楚我说的
know exactly what I mean when I
辅助功能是指什么
say accessibility well first of
那么我想说的是
all, I'm happy that you're here
首先  很高兴大家能来这里
and second, when we think about
第二  当我们一想到辅助功能
Accessibility it's really making
就应该明白它是真正能够让科技
technology usable by everyone
为人人所用
regardless of whatever their
而不管每个人的
unique needs might be.
需求有多么特别
At Apple, we approach this
在苹果公司  我们主要通过测试
problem by examining four major
四个不同等级的用户能力
classes of user ability,
来解决这个问题
cognitive, motor, vision and
它们分别是  认知能力  机动能力  视觉能力
hearing.
和听觉能力
Cognitive encompasses conditions
认知方面包括阅读障碍
like dyslexia or autism.
和自闭症等类似情况
Motor examines the way in which
机动能力是检测
a user physically interacts with
用户与系统之间的物理交互方式
the system, whether they need
看看它们是否需要
special accommodations for a
进行特别调整
condition like Parkinson's or
以便适应帕金森症或脑瘫症
cerebral palsy.
这样的情况
Vision which encompasses a range
视觉方面  包括了不同程度的
of visionability from those with
视觉能力
low vision conditions to those
从视力微弱的状态
who are completely blind.
到完全失明者的状态
And finally hearing which like
最后是听觉方面
vision encompasses a spectrum of
它就像视觉一样  包括了
hearing ability from those who
一系列不同程度的听力水平
are hard of hearing to those
从听力困难
that are completely deaf.
到完全失聪的状态
Worldwide there are over a
在世界范围内
billion people who have some
有超过十亿人
form of disability that fit into
存在着上述范畴包含的
one of those categories.
某种形式的能力障碍
Put another way, one in seven,
换句话说
one in seven people have a form
每七个人里面  就有一个人
of disability which means that
存在着某种能力障碍  这意味着
you're going to have and already
你可能会遇到或已经
do have users that have a
遇到了这样一些存在障碍的
disability.
的用户
But at the end of the day
然而归根结底
accessibility isn't about
辅助功能关注的
numbers it's about people.
并非数字  它关注的是人本身
in which people interact with
是人们与世界的
the world.
交互方式
It's about technology's
它关注的是科技赋予人类的潜能
transformative power to enable.
转换力量
It's about expanding the
以及怎样开拓
possibilities of what people can
人类活动发展的各种
do.
可能性
Accessibility is full of
在辅助功能的开发过程中
incredible stories, stories like
充满了不可思议的故事  就像Todd的
Todd's.
那些故事
In fact, we availed a video
其实我们已经制作好了一个系列视频
series highlighting some of
来记录这样一些故事
these stories and I'd like to
现在  我想和大家分享
share one of them with you now.
其中的一则故事
&gt;&gt; Now, are you going to be able
&gt;&gt;  好  你今天可以演奏吗
to play today or not, Morgan?
Morgan
All right, guys.
好的  朋友们
Ready to try it?
准备试一试吗
Let's try it.
我们开始吧
Clarinets, you up?
单簧管  你们起个调好不好
[ Music ]
[音乐]
Clarinets ready?
单簧管准备好了吗？
I love seeing the I got it face
我就爱看他们一脸“我明白了”的表情
when they understand and get
如果他们已经理解  已经明白了什么的话
something, you can actually see
你真的能够
it in their faces and that
从他们脸上看出来
encourages me to do more.
这激励着我去做更多的事情
[ Music ]
[音乐]
Clean music joke.
谁来讲个正经的音乐笑话
Howard, go.
Howard 你来
We tend to joke around the
我们喜欢在教室里讲笑话
classroom, I think that's part
我认为这是教学的一部分
of teaching let them see that
这让他们知道
you're human.
自己和别人没两样
I said a joke not two words, sit
我说的是讲个笑话  不是讲两个单词  请坐
down.
请坐下
&gt;&gt; No, it's a joke.
&gt;&gt;  不  这就是个笑话
[ Music ]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; That was not the best, was
&gt;&gt;  这并不是最棒的笑话
it?
对不对
For homework, the students they
做作业时  学生们把自己
record themselves playing.
的演奏过程录制好
[ Music ]
[音乐]
I can stream the music from the
我可以把音乐从 iPad 里导入
iPad into my hearing aids and
我的设备里面
actually it sounds like they're
听起来好像他们
right next to me, so I can grade
就在我身边演奏  这样我就可以
it right then and there.
随时随地给他们评分
Band is a family.
乐队就像一个家
[ Music ]
[音乐]
Once you walk in these doors it
只要你踏入这一间间房门
doesn't matter where you come
无论你来自哪里  都没有关系
from you're accepted.
这个家庭会接纳你
[ Music ]
[音乐]
And that'll be a dramatic pause
这应该是一个休止符
there.
这个位置
[ Music ]
[音乐]
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; So, we've gone about tackling
&gt;&gt;  因此  我们通过在所有平台上创建
problems that people like Shane
一系列广泛的系统功能
face every day by creating a
来帮助
wide array of baked in
像 Shane 这样的人
system-level features across all
解决每天
of our platforms.
所面临的问题
Which includes making sure that
这里面包括如何确保
our software works well with an
我们的软件能够运行良好
assortment of hardware
能够适用于
accessories made specifically
为残障人士专门制作的
for people with disabilities.
各种硬件设施
But at the end of the day what
但是归根结底  真正让
really makes Apple's platforms
苹果各项平台都变得强大的
great is the work that people
其实是你们这些人
like you do every day to make
每天在做的工作
sure that all of those amazing
这些工作确保你们
bits of content that you work on
取得了那些令人惊叹的成果
work for everyone.
并且服务于每一个人
So, with that in mind, let's
因此  说到这里
take a look at what we're going
让我们来看看今天要
to talk about today.
讨论的内容
The first thing I'd like to do
今天我首先想做的事情
is highlight some of our new
是重点介绍我们所有平台上
assistive features across all of
新增的一些
our platforms.
辅助功能
And from there I'd like to shift
我还想从这一点出发  顺便再谈谈
to talking about what you as a
大家作为一名开发人员
developer can do to make sure
究竟能够些做什么
that your stuff works with our
才可以确保你们的产品与我们的
stuff.
相配合
And that really starts by
让我们从头说起  其实
auditing your own app for
大家首先要核查一下自己App里的
accessibility, looking at what
辅助功能  看看
the current accessibility
当前的辅助功能体验
experience is like.
究竟是什么状况
And from there we're going to
然后我们继续
take a look at some of the
再来看一看
basics of our accessibility API
我们关于辅助功能 API 的
and the way that you can take
一些基本技术
advantage of it to solve some of
以及如何利用它来解决
the issues you find during your
你在审核过程中发现的
audit.
一些问题
From there we're going to go
再往后  我们就可以超越
beyond the basics to look at
基础阶段  去了解我们开发的
some of our more advanced APIs
一些更高级的 API
to help you solve some common
这样会有助于大家解决一些
problems that you might find
普遍存在的问题  大家在开发 App
while making your own apps
辅助功能时可能会遇到的
accessible.
问题
And finally, I'd like to spend a
最后  我还愿意再花些
little bit of time talking about
时间来谈谈
some accessibility
某些辅助功能方面
considerations that you should
的考虑  大家在使用 iOS 11 的
make when implementing the
拖放功能时
drag-and-drop in iOS 11.
需要考虑到这些
So, let's get started.
那么  下面我们就进入正题
The first feature I'd like to
今天我想介绍的
talk about today is text
第一个功能是
detection.
文本检测
So, let's imagine for a second
我们稍微想像一下
that you're a VoiceOver user
如果你是一位
who's blind and you're scrolling
失明的 VoiceOver 用户
through your favorite social
当你正在自己最喜欢的社交媒体
media app and you come across an
App 上滚动查找内容时
image like this where somebody
却遇到了这样的图片
has embedded text within an
有人在图像里面嵌入了
image.
文字
When you tap on it you're
当你轻点它的时候
probably not going to hear a
你听到的描述很可能
description of what's actually
跟图片的文字
in the image unless the
并不相符
developer has gone through and
除非开发人员已经检查过
done the work to put a label
并且替你完成了标记和
that describes it to you.
描述图片的工作
But this year in iOS 11, as well
但今年情况有所不同的是  在 iOS 11
as on macOS if you focus on an
或 macOS 系统里  如果你聚焦于
image we're going to do some
某张图片  我们就会做一些
basic text detection to try and
基础的文本检测
figure out if there's text
来检查并确定这张图片中
within that image and if it
是否有文本  如果文本自身是
makes sense to speak it then
有意义的内容
we're going to speak to the user
那么我们就会把它
and it sounds a little something
读出来给用户听  大体情况
like this.
就像是这样
&gt;&gt; Possible text, I can't
&gt;&gt;  可能的文本  我真是
believe I took this with my
不敢相信  这是我用 iPhone
iPhone.
拍出来的
&gt;&gt; Now along that same vein,
&gt;&gt;  现在按照同样的思路
we're introducing improved photo
我们在整个 VoiceOver 用户系统里
descriptions for VoiceOver users
也准备引入改进的照片
systemwide.
描述功能
So, when a VoiceOver user
这样的话  当 VoiceOver 用户
focuses on an image we're going
聚焦一张图片时
to run some basic analysis to
我们就会运行某种基本分析
try and figure out what's
并尝试弄清楚
contained within that image and
这张图里包含了什么
speak details about it so that
然后再给用户讲述细节
VoiceOver users get a richer
这样的话 VoiceOver 用户就可以获得更详细的
description.
描述
We look for things like the
比如说  我们要查找
number of faces within an image,
一张图片里的人脸数量
what expressions are they
他们是什么样的表情
making, what's the overall scene
图片的整体场景是什么
of that image, and what's its
它的模糊度
blurriness or brightness level.
或者亮度是多少
So, a description for an image
所以说  像这样一张图片的
like this one might sound like
描述可能听起来是
this.
这样的
&gt;&gt; One face, one smiling,
&gt;&gt;  一张脸  一个微笑
nightclub, blurry, bright.
酒吧  模糊的  明亮的
&gt;&gt; Now if you're a developer
&gt;&gt;  如果你是一个开发人员
who's already gone through and
已经尽职尽力地
done your due diligence of
给所有这些图片
labeling all your images don't
都做过标注  那么别担心
worry we're not just going to
我们并不准备
hijack that description from
直接盗用你的描述
you.
成果
Instead, if a user wants to hear
相反  如果用户想要听到
the description that we
我们自己生成的
ourselves have generated that
那部分描述
all they need to do is a single
他们只需用三根指头
three-finger tap on the image
轻点图像
and they'll hear our
然后就能听到我们的
description.
描述内容
Next, we have large texts.
再往下来  我们还有“更大字体”的功能
So, this year our team did an
今年我们的团队审核了
audit of the large text
全系统范围内
experience systemwide with a
大字号用户的使用体验
real focus on the experience of
并且重点审核了
those users who use our largest
那些使用辅助功能中
accessibility text sizes.
最大字号的用户
And we worked with teams across
我们与 Apple 的各个团队合作
Apple to really, really improve
真真正正地提升了
this experience, which also
大字号体验
includes some new APIs.
这里面还包括一些新的 API
Now there's a lot that I could
关于这个特色
say about this feature.
我还有很多可说的
In fact, there's so much that I
事实上  关于这个功能
could say about this feature
可以说的实在太多了
there's a whole other session
这次大会的一项议程就是
dedicated just to dynamic type
专门介绍 Dynamic Type 的
it's called Building Apps with
会议名称是“用 Dynamic Type
Dynamic Type.
构建 App”
It's going to be in the
在星期五下午举行
executive ballroom Friday at
1点50分
1:50 and I highly, highly
在高管宴会厅
recommend that you attend to
我强烈建议在座各位参加
figure out how to best adapt
并且了解清楚  怎样让自己的 App
your own apps for dynamic type
适应 iOS 11 里的 Dynamic Type
in iOS 11.
并且完成最佳调适
Now there are two other sessions
接下来我还想介绍
up here that I'd like to point
其他两个议程
out that also contain relevant
它们同样包含了
information about dynamic type.
有关 Dynamic Type 的信息
The first Design for Everyone is
第一个会议主题是“为每个人设计”
a session that focuses on the
它主要的关注点是
design of accessibility, but
辅助功能的设计
will also contain a portion that
但它也有一部分的内容
will cover dynamic type,
和 Dynamic Type 相关
including some of the rationale
包括我们为了适应大字体
behind decisions that we made
和各种设计考虑
when adapting the layouts for
而调整布局时做出的
large text and design
决定所遵循的基本原则
considerations that you yourself
这也是大家在自己设计 App 时
should make when designing your
需要考虑和决定
own apps.
的问题
And second, Auto Layout
第二个会议主题是
Techniques in Interface Builder
“Interface Builder 的自动布局技术”
will have a portion dedicated to
这个议程的部分内容  是讨论
adapting your layouts that are
如何根据 Dynamic Type 的需求
built with interface builder for
而使用 Interface Builder
dynamic type.
来调整应用布局的内容
So, I hope to see you all at
我希望能在这些会议上
these sessions.
见到你们所有人
Moving on, we have the
接着往下讲  我们还新增了
Accessibility keyboard.
辅助功能键盘
This is a feature built for
这是基于 macOS
macOS for users who have enough
而打造的一项性能
dexterity to use a trackpad, but
它适用于能够熟练使用触控板
can't necessarily use a physical
而又不一定使用
keyboard.
实体键盘的人
It's an onscreen keyboard that
它是一个屏幕键盘
has things like system controls
上面有些东西  比如说系统控制键
and a predictive text bar and is
还有输入预测条
fully customizable, which means
它完全可以进行自定义修改
that if I have certain actions
也就是说  如果我每天都有一些
that I do on a daily basis that
固定的操作步骤
I want to create a custom panel
于是想创建一个自定义面板
for so I just have to click it
那么我只需点击一下它
once and it'll initiate that
就会启动那项日常操作
action then I can create those
我就可以用这种方式
panels.
创建个人面板了
So, for instance if I email my
举个例子  如果我每天
manager every day I may create a
都要给我的经理发邮件
custom panel that opens mail,
那我就可以创建一个自定义面板
composes an email, and adds her
它帮我打开邮箱  撰写邮件
address in there.
再把邮箱地址加在这里
Next, we have Type to Siri, so
下一个  我们来说说 Type to Siri 的功能
like the title suggests this
就像这个名称所表明的那样
feature allows you to interact
这个功能让大家能够通过
with Siri via text input like
文本输入的形式与 Siri 交互
you would via speech.
就像我们平常说话交流一样
And we're really excited about
我们为此而感到格外振奋
this because it's going to open
因为它将为一大批
up Siri to a class of users who
因为不能开口说话
are unable to use it before,
而一直无法使用 Siri 的人
those who are nonverbal.
开启一扇新的大门
Finally, we have Smart Invert
最后  我们要介绍的功能
Colors.
Smart Invert Colors
So, previously on iOS if you
在以前的 iOS 系统里
enabled the invert colors
如果你开启了“颜色反转”这个功能
feature it would invert all the
它就会把你设备上
content of your device
所有内容的颜色反转过来
regardless of what kind of
不管它的具体内容
content it is.
是什么
But this year we're introducing
但是今年  我们要引入
Smart Invert Colors, which looks
Smart Invert Colors
at specific kinds of content
它关注特定类型的内容
like graphics or images and
比如说图表或照片
doesn't invert them so that you
它不会反转这类内容的颜色
can see the content as it was
这样你眼中所见的东西
actually meant to be.
就是它们原来的样子
Now I'd actually like to do a
我想在今天的现场
demo of that feature for you
演示一下这个功能
now.
给大家看
So, I have my device here and
我这儿有一台设备
I'm going to enable Smart Invert
我要启用 Smart Invert Colors
Colors.
功能
Now as you can see, the
现在你们可以看见  这个
wallpaper wasn't inverted nor
壁纸的颜色并没有反转
were all of the app icons.
所有的 App 图标也都没有
And if I go into my Photos app,
如果我进入我的“照片”这个应用
you'll see that I still have the
可以看见用户界面
dark UI that is important for
依然是黑色的  对于那些使用
users who use invert colors that
颜色反转功能
have certain low-vision
但又处于可见度较差环境的情况
conditions where a white UI
能做到这一点很重要
makes the display too difficult
因为白色的用户界面
to look at for prolonged periods
会让人很难长时间注视它的
of time.
展示内容
So, I can still see my photos as
所以  我现在看到的照片
they originally were.
仍然是它们原来的样子
Now if I go to an app like Clock
现在  如果我进入另一个 App 比如时钟
which already had a dark UI
它的用户界面已经是暗色
you'll also notice that we
这时你就会发现
haven't inverted that UI to keep
我们并没有反转用户界面颜色
the dark look around that is so
而是保留原来的暗色
important to our invert colors
这对于使用颜色反转的用户来说
users.
十分重要
Now that's just a very basic
以上这些  只是对“反转颜色”
overview of that feature and I
这一功能的基本概述
highly recommend that you check
我强烈建议大家
it out yourself and see how it
自己尝试一下
plays around with your own apps.
看看它在你的 App 里如何运作
But now I'd like to pivot into
但是现在  我要围绕另一个话题
talking about the experience of
谈谈  那就是大家作为一名
you as a developer and how you
开发人员的体验  以及你
make sure that all of your work
如何确保在自己所有的工作中
works with all the things that I
都能够使用我刚才提及的
just covered, as well as all of
这些新功能
our old features.
以及我们所有的那些旧功能
And that really begins by
那么接下来大家就要从
auditing your app for
检查自己 App 的
accessibility.
辅助功能开始
So, when we're starting an audit
当我们开始检查时
the first thing you're going to
你要做的第一件事
want to do is enable an
就是打开一项
accessible technology like
辅助功能技术
Voiceover or Switch Control and
比如  画外音 Voiceover  或切换控制
see what the experience is like
然后感受一下 VoiceOver
for a Voiceover user.
用户会有怎样的体验
So, to do that we're going to
那么接下来  就让我们
tap on General Accessibility and
轻点“通用”选项 找到“辅助功能”并打开
go down to this accessibility
向下翻  找到“辅助功能快捷键”
shortcut page and add VoiceOver
将 VoiceOver 添加
to our shortcut.
到快捷键
What this does is that now
这样做的结果是
whenever I triple click the Home
无论何时  当我连续三次点击 Home 按钮时
button VoiceOver will turn on
就会启动 VioceOver
and if I have VoiceOver on
如果我已经打开了 VoiceOver
already it will turn VoiceOver
它就会关闭 VoiceOver
off so I can quickly cycle
这样我就能够在使用
between the two as I'm going
App 的过程中  快速地
through my app.
在这两种状态之间切换
And now that we have VoiceOver
现在我们已经把 VoiceOver
on.
打开了
We're going to Home out of
我们要退出“设置”  并返回主屏幕
settings and go to the app that
再进入我们想要检查的 App
we want to audit and just start
我们想要核查一下  只是试用
playing around to see what the
看看 VoiceOver 的用户
experience is like for a
他们的体验究竟
VoiceOver user.
是怎样
Are all the things that I would
我希望对用户可见的东西
expect to be visible visible?
它们已经全部可见了吗
Are the things that I would not
所有那些我希望
want to be visible to a
对 VoiceOver 用户
VoiceOver user not visible to
不可见的东西  已经都是
them?
不可见了吗
Does every interaction with the
与界面的每一次交互
interface have some sort of
是否在某种程度上都必然
corollary that a VoiceOver user
能让 VoiceOver 用户
can take advantage of?
从中获益？
And does the UI itself make
用户界面自身是否合理
sense, does the flow make sense?
整个流程是否合理
As well are elements properly
还有界面上的哪些元素没有被
labeled?
正确标识？
For instance, I would expect
举个例子  我希望
this button that's an upload
这个用来点赞的按钮
button to be labeled upload tell
可以标识为“点赞”  并且告诉我
me it has three votes currently
它目前一共收到了三个赞
and that it's a button.
而且  这就是个按钮
Now we have a tool called the
现在 我们已经有一款工具
Accessibility Inspector that can
名叫 Accessibiliy Inspector
also be used for auditing your
它也可以用来核查你的
apps.
App
You can get to it by going to
你可以通过 Xcode 找到它
Xcode, open Developer Tool and
打开“开发者工具”
opening the Accessibility
再打开 Accessibiliy
Inspector.
Inspector
And what this tool allows you to
这款工具可以帮你做的事
do is look at specific elements
是找到屏幕上的
of your screen and get their
特定元素  并且获取它们的
accessibility information, as
辅助功能信息
well as run a full audit of the
同时对你 App 里面的
accessibility in your app.
辅助功能进行全面检查
Now I'm not going to cover using
我今天不准备介绍这款工具的
this tool today, but there was a
使用方法  但是在去年的
session at last year's WWDC that
WWDC 上有一项议程
covered extensively how you take
它全面涵盖了如何利用
advantage of this app and work
这个 App 以及如何将它应用到
it into your own workflow.
你自己工作流程的各项事宜
So, if you're interested in that
所以  如果你对此感兴趣的话
I recommend that you check it
我建议你们大家通过
out at this link.
这个链接查看一下
Instead, what I like to do now
我现在要演示给大家的
for you is demo auditing a
是如何检查一个 App 样本
sample app that I've been
这是我最近在琢磨的
working on.
一个 App
So, I'm going to come to my
好 我现在请大家看看我的
device here and you can see I
设备界面  你们可以看见
have this app down in the corner
右下角的这个 App
called Pre-Poster.
名叫 Pre-Poster
Now this is an app I've been
这是我正在使用的一个 App
working on that allows me to
它能让我把帖子
post posts to a social network
发布到一个社交网络上
to a close group of friends
给一群关系密切的朋友看
before I post it to the wider
在此之后  我再把它发布到范围更广的
social network to make sure I
社交网络上  这样是为了确保
have all my friends' approval of
我所有的朋友都会支持
those things I'm posting.
我要发布的这些东西
Now I have things like up vote
我在这上面有好些东西  比如支持键
buttons and down vote buttons so
还有反对键  这样的话
that friends can tell me whether
朋友们就可以告诉我
it's good or not, comments, I
我的帖子是好是坏  并且给予评论
have even star ratings so that I
我甚至还设置了星级评分  这样我就
can rate how good a post is, and
可以评估一个帖子的好坏程度
I have settings that allow me to
这里有“设置”功能  可以让我
set which social networks I want
设置一下  哪些社交网络是我希望
to automatically post to when
在计时结束时
the timer runs down.
自动登录发帖的
So, let's turn on VoiceOver and
现在  让我们打开 VoiceOver
just see what we find.
看看能有什么发现
I'm going to triple click the
我准备连续三次点击
Home button and as you can see,
Home 按钮  现在大家可以看到
I have my accessibility
我的辅助功能快捷键
shortcuts to include the
里面包括了
VoiceOver and Smart Invert and
VoiceOver 和 Smart Invert
I'm going to select VoiceOver.
我现在选择 VoiceOver
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver on Pre-Poster Tom
&gt;&gt;  VoiceOver 启动 Pre-Poster
McNeil, [inaudible] button,
Tom McNeil 按钮
three button, button, two open
按钮  三  按钮  两条公开
posts.
帖子
&gt;&gt; So, I'm swiping my finger
&gt;&gt;  所以  我现在用手指轻扫一下
with VoiceOver to navigate
让 VoiceOver 帮助我浏览
between elements onscreen and I
屏幕上的不同元素  然后
noticed a couple of things
我注意到
there.
这里面有一些问题
First of all, elements were out
首先  那些元素
of order.
是杂乱无序的
I swiped from one label to the
我再轻扫一下  从一个按钮标签换到
buttons to the second label.
第二个按钮标签
Both labels didn't give me any
两个标签都没有给我任何
indication that I can actually
指示  我不知道能否真的通过
tap on them to go into my own
点击它们  而进入我自己的
profile and see all my own
个人页面  然后看到自己所有的
posts.
帖子
And all of those buttons were
所有这些按钮都
missing labels to tell me what
缺少标签  所以无法告诉我
they actually do and what
它们的实际功能是什么  以及
they're meant to be.
它们有什么含义
So, let's keep going.
好  我们继续
&gt;&gt; Lexi Torres five minutes
&gt;&gt;  Lexi Torres  还剩五分钟
remaining, just finished my set
我刚设置完
three comments, two button,
三条评论  按钮  二
three button.
按钮  三
&gt;&gt; Now those two buttons have
&gt;&gt;  现在  这两个按钮是具有
their values because I'm storing
实际值的  因为我把
the number of votes in the
投票的数量保存在
buttons text label so VoiceOver
按钮的文本标签里  所以 VoiceOver
is able to read that, but again
能够把它朗读出来  但是
they're unlabeled because I have
它们的标签仍没被设置好  因为我并不知道
no idea what those buttons
这些按钮
actually do, what is the three
究竟是干什么的  那个“三”
ore the two associated with.
或者“二”究竟与什么有关
I'm going to come down here and
我现在下移到这里
I'm going to try and focus on
接下来  我准备集中讨论一下
the star view.
星级评分的视图
What you're hearing is VoiceOver
你现在听到的声音是 VoiceOver
indicating to the user that
在提示用户
there's no accessible element
在我手指触碰的位置
underneath my finger.
并没有可以访问的元素
And that means that the star
这意味着“星级视图”
view is not accessible at all so
根本无法访问  因此
we're going to need to fix that.
我们需要对它进行修复
&gt;&gt; Button.
&gt;&gt;  按钮
&gt;&gt; Let's check out the settings
&gt;&gt;  我们来检查一下
page.
设置页面
&gt;&gt; Settings close button.
&gt;&gt;  设置关闭按钮
&gt;&gt; That seems to be labeled
&gt;&gt;  这里的标签设置似乎是
properly.
正确的
&gt;&gt; Facebook, Facebook.
&gt;&gt; Facebook  Facebook
&gt;&gt; So, two things I notice here.
&gt;&gt; 我注意到这里有两样东西
First of all, the cell isn't
首先  这一单元格没有
indicating to me whether or not
提示我  这个设置功能
the setting is actually enabled.
是否已经被真正启用
And secondly, when I did a
其次  当我双击
double tap to activate it I
来激活它的时候
would expect it to enable or
我希望它可以启用
disable the setting and that
或禁用该设置
didn't happen either.
然而这种情况也没发生
&gt;&gt; Close.
&gt;&gt; 关掉
&gt;&gt; Now one other thing I
&gt;&gt; 我注意到另外
noticed.
一件事
&gt;&gt; Tom McNeil.
&gt;&gt; Tom McNeil
&gt;&gt; Is that when I was swiping
&gt;&gt; 我在翻看自己这个帖子的
through items on my post it gave
项目内容时  它是不是
me no indication that I can
完全没有提示说
actually delete the post.
我其实可以删帖
When I'm not using VoiceOver if
如果我不准备使用 VoiceOver
I do a long press on one of
然后再长按其中的
these cells it brings up an
一个单元格  就会出现
action sheet to initiate a
一个操作表单  并启动
delete.
删除功能
But that interaction isn't clear
但是这种交互功能对于
to a VoiceOver user at all and
VoiceOver 用户来说  并非显而易见
they have no way of initiating
而且用户也没办法
it.
启用它
&gt;&gt; Alert accessibility short
&gt;&gt; 警示  辅助功能快捷键
VoiceOver off.
VoiceOver 关闭
&gt;&gt; So, let's take a look at some
&gt;&gt; 那么  让我们看看
of the basics of our API to
我们自己的 API 里有哪些基础功能
solve these problems.
可以解决这些问题
Just to recap, this is what we
简要概括一下  这是我们先前
found.
的发现
First, we had elements that were
首先  我们发现有些杂乱无序的元素
out of order and my profile
以及我的个人主页元素
elements didn't indicate that I
并没有提示我可以
could tap on them to get to my
通过点击它们来
own profile so it really makes
进入自己的主页  所以确实有必要
sense to group them together as
把它们再组合起来
a single element that acts as a
作为单个的元素  形成一个
button.
按钮
Next, I have unlabeled buttons
其次  我这个 App 的顶部还有未设标签的按钮
on the top, as well as these on
单元格里的这些按钮也是没有
the cell.
标签
The star view was entirely
“星级视图”则完全
inaccessible, as was initiating
无法访问  删帖的功能
a delete of a post.
也无法启用
And finally, the settings didn't
最后  “设置”这一栏里并没有提示我
tell me whether or not they were
这些功能是否已被启用
enabled and an activate of them
另外  就算激活它们
didn't actually change the
也不能真正改变
value.
它们的值
So, how do we solve them?
那么  我们如何解决这些问题
Well when a technology like
像 VoiceOver 这样一种
VoiceOver is trying to get
技术  当它试图要获得
information about an element for
App 里的某项元素信息  也就是说
an app, so when a VoiceOver user
当 VoiceOver 用户
focuses on an element on the
关注屏幕上的某项元素时
screen it's going to ask a
它就会提出
couple of questions.
几个问题
Questions like what are you, I'm
比如  你是做什么的
a button?
我是一个按钮
Who are you, I'm a Notifications
你是谁
button?
我是一个通知按钮
What's your value, three unread
你的值是什么
notifications?
三条未读通知
Now all of these questions and
现在所有这些问题和答案
answers correspond to properties
都对应着代码当中的属性
in code and return specific
而且将返回特定的
kinds of return values.
返回值
So, let's take a look at this.
那么让我们来看一下
Here we have the five basic
我们在辅助功能协议里面
properties in the accessibility
设有五个基本属性
protocol and we're going to go
我们将通过
through them one by one looking
下面的例子
at an example.
来分别介绍它们
So, the first
第一个是
isAccessibilityElement indicates
isAccessibilityElement 属性  它指向
to a technology like VoiceOver
某种类似于 VoiceOver
or Switch Control whether the
或 Switch Control 这类技术  也就是要看
given element should be visible
某个指定元素究竟该不该对
to VoiceOver at all.
VoiceOver 可见
So, if we're looking at the
我们来看
memory view up in the corner
上方这一角的回忆视图
there that has a slideshow of
在这个“回忆”栏里
images within the memory, a
是多个图像构成的幻灯片  还有
label with the title, as well as
带标题的标签  以及
a play button that's a great
一个播放按钮  这是
candidate for making a button,
制作按钮的绝佳选择
the overall element a button
所有这些元素制成一个按钮
that when I tap on plays the
当我点击它  就会播放
movie.
电影
So, I'm going to set
所以  我准备把
isAccessibilityElement to be
“回忆”视图里的 isAccessibilityElement
true on that memory view.
属性值设置为 True
But now because of the way that
但是  现在因为我已经用这种方式
I've coded this it's possible
写编码了  这个播放按钮
that this play button is still
还是有可能会
going to come up as an
作为 VoiceOver 的
accessible element to VoiceOver
可访问元素出现
and because I'm making that
而且  因为我要把
overall element the target
这个整体元素作为最终目标
instead then I want to set this
因此我就把这个
play button's is excessively
播放按钮的
element to be false so that it
isAccessibilityElement 属性值设为 False
doesn't come up and we don't
这样一来  在这个地方就不会出现
have redundancy there.
功能上的重复了
And one thing that I forgot to
有一点我刚才忘记
mention is that it's a good idea
说的是  把这样一大块区域
to make the big area the play
转变成一个播放按钮
button instead because if I'm a
是个好主意  因为如果我是一名
VoiceOver user navigating around
VoiceOver 用户  我在浏览这个
this UI with by just feeling my
用户界面时  仅凭着手指
finger around the screen it's
感觉在屏幕上滑动
much harder to find that tiny
就很难找到那个小按钮
play button to play the movie
并且播放电影
than it is to find that big
相比之下  找到这样一大块区域
area.
就容易得多
Next, we have accessibilityLabel
接下来要介绍 accessibilityLabel 属性
which describes what an element
它描述的问题是  这个元素
is.
是什么
So, for example with our memory
例如  对于我们的“回忆”视图来说
view it's a memory and its title
它就是回忆  它的标题是
is February 18th, 2017.
“2017 年 2 月 18 日”
So, that seems like a reasonable
所以  这看上去是一个合理的
label.
标签
But now because we're going to
但现在  因为我们要
be treating it like a button you
使它具有按钮的功能
might wonder why we don't add
你可能想知道  我们为什么
the word button into our label
不把“按钮”一词添加到标签中
and that's because of this next
这样做的原因  是因为下一个属性
property, accessibilityTraits.
accessibilityTraits
This indicates to VoiceOver what
它向 VoiceOver 表明
category an element fits into.
某个元素适合哪一类别
So, for example we're going to
例如  我们准备要把
set our memory view
“回忆”视图里的
accessibilityTraits to include
accessibilityTraits 属性设置为
the button trait so that
包含按钮特性  这样的话
VoiceOver knows to treat it like
VoiceOver 就知道要把它当作
a button.
按钮来使用
This also means that when it
这也意味着  当它
reads the description for the
读出这一项的具体描述时
item it's going to say button at
会在结尾处
the end of that so that the user
加上“按钮”一词  这样用户就
knows what it is.
知道它是什么了
Now traits are also important
除此之外  特性的重要性
for two more reasons.
还体现在另外两个方面
One, they can afford certain UI
第一  他们可以实现特定的
behaviors which you'll see you
用户界面行为  你可以
later in the presentation.
在稍后的展示中看到
And two, there's mechanisms for
第二  我们有一个用户机制
users to navigate the interface
可以让用户按照特定类型的
based on specific kinds of items
项目来浏览界面
that will be surfaced based on
而这些项将按照
what traits are associated with
与之相关联的特性进行
it.
显示
Next, we have accessibilityValue
接下来  我们要谈谈 accessibilityValue 属性
which is for elements that have
它适用于处于
some form of state.
某种状态的元素
So, for instance if we're in our
例如  如果我们
memory video and we're editing
在观看“回忆”幻灯片时  并且要编辑它
there's a scrubber along the
这时在界面底部就有一个
bottom that allows me to scrub
数据清理器  可以让我对整个
through the whole video.
音像进行清理
And the current valve of that
这个清理器的当前值
item is the second that I'm
是我聚焦的某一秒钟  它属于
focused on of the elapsed
已经发生
seconds that have already
的几秒钟的消耗
happened.
时间
So, I can set its accessibility
所以我可以把这个 acessibilityValue
value to be that elapsed number
的值设置为我正在观看的
of seconds that I'm currently
当前视频所消耗的
looking at.
几秒钟时间
Finally, we have
最后  我们要谈谈
accessibilityHint.
accessibilityHint
Now this is meant to be a more
它代表了一段
longform description of how to
更长形式的描述
interact with an element, what
介绍应该如何与某元素进行交互
it does or what it's meant for.
它的作用是什么  或者它的设置目的是什么
You can think of this as being a
你可以把它想象为这样一种
property that allows you to
属性  它帮助你向
describe to a user that's new to
用户描述  你的界面上
your interface and help them
有哪些新功能  并且帮助他们
learn how to use your interface.
了解如何使用你的界面
But it's important that you
但重要的是
never put critical information
你绝不能把任何针对用户的
to whoever's using it in a hint
关键信息放在 Hint 里
because hints can actually be
因为对于有经验的用户来说
disabled to keep VoiceOver from
他们为了不让 VoiceOver 变得
being too verbose for
太繁琐  实际上有可能会
experienced users.
禁用 Hint 的提示功能
So, going a little further.
现在  让我们详细介绍
New this year we have attributed
今年  我们加入了一些
versions of label, value and
新版的标签值以及
hint.
提示
And what these allow you to do
这些属性可以让你
is pass through specific keys to
通过修改特定的键值
tweak the way in which VoiceOver
来改变 VoiceOver 朗读一连串字符
speaks a string.
的方式
So, for example if I have a
比如说  如果我有一行
string that I know I want to
字符串  我希望把它念出来
speak -- that's in a different
它使用了另一种不同的
language and should be spoken
语言  应该通过这种语言专用的
with a different voice
另一种声音合成器来
synthesizer specific to that
把它朗读出来
language then I can use the
这样我就可以通过
UIAccessibilitySpeech
正确的语言代码  来使用
AttributeLanguage key and pass
UIAccessibilitySpeech
in the correct language code so
AttributeLanguage 键
that when VoiceOver speaks it,
因此  当 VoiceOver 朗读这个字符串时
it speaks it with say in this
使用的目标语言  就像这个例子展示的那样
example, the French synthesizer.
是法语语言合成器
Now as well let's say I had an
另外  还可以再举个例子  假如说我要
announcement that I wanted to
发布一条通知  我想要发布
post and speak, but I felt like
并让 VoiceOver 朗读出来  但是我觉得
that announcement isn't
这条通知并没有那么重要
important enough to interrupt
我不想因为它而中断
whatever current speech is
VoiceOver 当前在进行
happening.
的任何朗读
Well in this case I can use an
在这个例子中  我可以使用
attributed string with the
一个具有 UIAccessibilitySpeech
UIAccessibilitySpeech
AttributeQueueAnnouncement
AttributeQueueAnnouncement that
属性的字符串
will queue the speech behind
它会让这条通知的朗读
whatever existing speech is
排列到正在朗读的内容
already there so that it will be
后面  这样只有当
spoken whatever VoiceOver was
VoiceOver 完成了当前的朗读
already speaking is done.
才会开始朗读那条通知
Also, new this year we have the
此外  我们今年还引入了新的
concept of containers.
容器概念
So previously, when a VoiceOver
在这之前  当 VoiceOver
user would swipe into a
用户用手指轻扫并进入
container of some kind they
某种类型的容器时
wouldn't really get an
他们并不会真正得到
indication of what kind of thing
相应的提示来告知他们
they were swiping into, what
刚进入的界面是什么
does those content actually even
以及界面里的这些内容究竟意味着
mean.
什么
So, we're introducing
现在我们来介绍
accessibilityContainerType where
accessibilityContainerType
you can define this and there
大家可以通过定义这个键值来实现上述目标
are several different kinds of
而容器的类型可以有
containers.
很多种
The biggest one there is
最大的一种就是
dataTable which actually
dataTable  它确实
requires conformance to the UI
需要遵循 UI Accessibility
accessibility container
Container dataTable 协议
dataTable protocol and improves
内容  它改进了
the way in which a VoiceOver
VoiceOver 用户在你的
user can navigate through your
dataTable 里的浏览方式
dataTable and understand where
并且清楚它们的位置
they are.
所在
So, everything that I just
那么  刚才我提到的
covered there applies to views
都是适用于你使用
that you would use through UIKit
UIkit 框架构建出的界面
you.
视图
But what if your controls exist
但是如果你的控件
out of UIKit, you have some sort
并不在 UIKit 里  你的某一种
of non-view element that perhaps
非可视元素  可能
you've drawn using core
是你使用核芯显卡提取出来的  那么
graphics.
该怎么办
Well in that case we still need
在这种情况下  我们仍然需要
to surface those controls to
让那些控件对 VoiceOver
VoiceOver and so we're going to
是可见的  所以我们准备
use UI accessibilityElement to
使用 UI accessibilityElement
represent logical accessible
来代表屏幕上那些逻辑排布
regions of the screen to
可获取区域
basically stand in for those
让它们来取代那些
controls.
控件
So, UI accessibilityElement you
所以  你要在 UI AccessibilityElement
set all the properties that I
设置好我刚说的
covered before on it like you
所有属性  就像大家在
would on any other view and it's
其他任何视图里设置的那样
initialized with an
那么它就会在 accessibility
accessibility container that
Container 这个容器里完成预置
would be the view that it's
这个辅助功能容器就成为
contained in.
容纳它的那个视图
And then you override on the
然后你就在这个容器里
container the
覆写
accessibilityElements protocol
accessibilityElements 协议
which tells VoiceOver what sub
这个协议会告诉 VoiceOver  某个视图
elements within a view are the
里面的哪些子元素
accessible elements.
是可获取的元素
And the order in which elements
在这个数组里返回的
are returned in this array is
这些元素的顺序
the order in which VoiceOver
就是 VoiceOver
will swipe through them.
掠扫过它们的顺序
So that seems like a great
这就好像是一个理想对象
candidate for combining those
它可以把个人页面的
profile elements into a single
多项元素整合为
element.
单个元素
So, let's come back over to our
所以  让我们回到一开始的
sample app and take a look at
样本 App 看看如何
implementing some of these
运用这样一些最基本的
basics.
功能
Okay, so I have -- I'm in my
好的  现在我要
home view controller which is
在我的首页视图控制器里
the main screen I'm on and the
也就是主页面
first I want to do is fix the
我首先要做的  就是修复
labels for those buttons that
那些位于顶部的
are up on the top.
按钮标签
So, for the add button I'm going
我把“添加”按钮的标签
to say new post because it
设置为“新帖”
creates a new post.
因为它会创建一个新的发帖请求
The notifications button I'm
把“通知”按钮的标签
going to set its label to be
设置为“通知”
notifications and its value to
然后将它的值
be my current number of unread
设置为我现在的未读
notifications.
通知数量
And then the settings button I'm
接着再把“设置”按钮的标签
going to set to be settings.
确定为“设置”
Now I'm going to go take care of
现在我再来打量一下
those other unlabeled buttons
其他还没有贴标签的按钮
that were my upload and download
比如“点赞”和“反对”
buttons.
按钮
So, for my approved button I'm
我准备把我的“赞成”按钮
going to set its label to be up
设置为“点赞”标签
vote and for my disapprove
把“不赞成”按钮的标签
button down vote.
设置为“反对”
Now I need to also remember to
现在我可不能忘了
change the accessibility value
只要赞成数和反对数发生变化
of these buttons whenever my
我就需要改变
number of approves or number of
这些按钮的
disapproves changes.
辅助功能值
So, when I come into here I'm
所以当我走到这一步时
going to make a switch statement
我要根据赞同的数量
based on number of approves.
添加一条“切换”语句
When it's one I'm going to say
当赞同数是 1 时  我要表明
it's the number of approves vote
这是单个赞同的数量
or when it's more than one I'm
当赞同数大于 1 时
going to day number of approves
我要表明这是多个赞同
votes.
的数量
And I'm going to do the same
然后我再
thing.
在“反对”部分
For the disapprove.
进行相同的操作
So, let's go to the star view
接下来  我们来看“星级视图”部分
which was previously
它之前是无法访问的
inaccessible and we're going to
我们现在要将它
make that an accessible element.
转换为可访问元素
The first thing that we're going
首先  我们要做的事
to do is override
是重写
isAccessibilityElement to return
isAccessibilityElement  把返回值改成
true so that VoiceOver knows
“return True”  这样 VoiceOver 就知道
that this is an element it
这是它应该关注的
should focus on.
元素
Going to set its label to be
将 accessibilityLabel 的返回值设为
star rating because that's what
星级评分  因为
it is.
它应该显示这个
And then for its value based on
然后是它以评星数量为基础的值
the number of stars we're going
这个我们准备让它
to return either no rating, one
返回 “不评分”  “1 星”
star or the current number of
或者当前评星的
stars.
的总数
So now let's come back to the
那么现在我们回到
home view controller where we
首页视图控件  在这里
had those labels that we wanted
我们将想要的这些标签
to join together to be a single
合并到一起  变成单个的
element that acted like a
元素  并且形成
button.
一个按钮
So, what we're going to do for
那么  我们接下来就要做
that is a couple things.
下面几件事
We're going to create a UI
我们要创建一个
accessibilityElement the
UI AccessibilityElement
container of which is the header
它的 Container 值为“header View”
view and then we're going to set
然后我们要把它的标签
its label to be my profile name,
设置为我的用户配置文件名
its value to be my number of
它的 Value  设置为我打开的
open posts, and its traits to
端口数量  它的 Traits 设置为
include the button traits so the
包含按钮特性  这样一来
user knows that they can
用户就知道他们可以
interact with it like a button.
把它当作一个按钮交互
And then I'm going to find its
接着  我要找到它的
frame and set this property
Frame  并且设置这个属性
accessibilityFrame
accessibilityFrame
InContainerSpace.
InContainerSpace
Now this is important because
这一步非常重要
for a couple reasons.
原因有几个方面
It's telling VoiceOver where the
它会告诉 VoiceOver
element is onscreen and the
这个元素位于屏幕的哪个位置
coordinate space of its
以及它的容器所在的
container which is used to draw
座标空间  它可以用来绘制
the bounding box, as well as
边界框  而且
when a VoiceOver user is feeling
当某位 VoiceOver 用户在
around the screen for elements
屏幕上摸索寻找元素时
it's using this property to
这个属性可以用来
detect whether or not an element
检测一个元素是否
can be found underneath their
能在手指触摸时
finger.
被找到
Finally, on our header view,
最后  在我们的页头视图中
we're going to set our
我们现在要设置
accessibilityElements to contain
accessibilityElements 来包含
our new element plus those three
我们的新元素  以及那三个
buttons that we had already.
已有的按钮
Last but not least, I want to
最后同样重要的是  我想看看
come to the switch cell and make
开关单元格  并且
this the whole cell an
把整个单元格变成一个
accessibility element and for
辅助功能元素  并且
its value based on whether or
根据当前开关是否已开启
not the switch is currently on
来确定它的“Value”值
I'm going to say on or off as
我会说“On”或者“Off”
its accessibility value.
作为它的辅助功能值
So, let me build that to my
那么  我把它创建在我的
device.
设备上
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver on mail, no unread
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver 开启邮件  没有未读
emails.
邮件
Double tap to open.
双击打开
Sorry, give me one sec.
对不起  稍等片刻
&gt;&gt; Alert, selected.
&gt;&gt; 警示  已选中
&gt;&gt; Okay well I have thankfully a
&gt;&gt; 好吧  幸好我有一个
premade version of this that
预先做好的版本
actually already has the
而且这个版本里确实已经装好了
accessibility in it so we're
辅助功能  所以我们要
going to launch that and I'm
启动它  然后
going to turn on VoiceOver.
打开 VoiceOver
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver on Pre-Poster EX
&gt;&gt; VoiceOver 开启  预发布执行者
Tom McNeil two open posts
Tom McNeil 两个公开发帖
button.
按钮
&gt;&gt; And the first thing that you
&gt;&gt; 你们最先能看到的
see is that I have joined those
是我把这些元素合并到
elements together and that it's
一起  这里有语音
spoken that it's a button.
这是一个按钮
&gt;&gt; Tap the add button,
&gt;&gt; 轻点“添加”按钮
notifications three, button
通知 3 条  按钮
settings button.
“设置”按钮
&gt;&gt; All those buttons have proper
&gt;&gt; 所有这些按钮都有正确的
labels.
标签
&gt;&gt; Down vote two button, up vote
&gt;&gt; 向上反对 2 按钮  向上点赞
three button.
3 按钮
&gt;&gt; Those have proper labels as
&gt;&gt; 这些也都有正确的
well.
标签
&gt;&gt; Page two of four star rating,
&gt;&gt; 星级评分  第二页  共四页
no rating, adjustable.
未评分  可调整
I can focus on the star, sorry.
我可以关注一下这个星星  噢我说错了
I can focus on the star rating
我可以关注这个星级评分
view, it's actually a view now.
视图  它现在确实是一个视图了
If I go into my settings.
如果我进入我的设置
&gt;&gt; Settings, setting, Facebook
&gt;&gt; 设置  Facebook
off.
关闭
&gt;&gt; I'm finally actually reading
&gt;&gt; 我要查看的是
whether or not my setting is
我的设置状态目前到底是
currently off or on.
开还是关
Now there are a couple of
现在  我们在审核过程中
problems that we found during
发现了一些问题
our audit that we still haven't
我们仍然没有
actually fixed.
完全修复它们
I still have no way of bringing
我暂时还无法打开
up the delete sheet.
删除表单
I have no way of actually
也没法真正
changing the value of the star
更改星级评分
rating view.
视图的值
I can see what it is, I can see
我能认出它是什么
what the current number stars
能看见它现在有几星
is, but I have no way of
但我没办法
changing it.
改动它
And when I double tap on my
当我双击设置键
setting it's still not changing
仍然不能改变
that setting value.
这个设置的值
So, the first thing I want to
所以  我想做的第一件事
look at are custom actions.
是看一下自定义操作
So, we're going to use these to
我们要用这些操作来打开
bring up that delete sheet in
这个样本 App 里的
our sample app.
删除表单
Basically, a custom action is
从根本上来说  自定义操作就是
something that you add to an
你把某样东西添加到一个元素
element that is an action that
这是它可以使用的
it has available to it.
一种操作
So, views have the property
所以  视图拥有这个
accessibilityCustomActions which
accessibilityCustomActions 属性
you can override with an array
你可以使用一个
of UI accessibilityCustomAction
UI AccessibilityCustomAction 的数组来覆盖
that are all of the actions
这些是它所有能用得上的
available to it.
操作
So, what does an action look
那么一项操作
like?
到底是什么样的呢
Well it has a name for instance,
具体举例来说  它有个名称
our delete action is called
我们的删除操作就叫“delete”
delete because it tells the user
因为这样就可以告诉用户
what it does and it has a target
它是做什么的  然后它还有
and a selector that get called
一个目标和一个选择器
whenever that action is
只要一启动这项操作  这两个都会
initiated.
被调用
So, when a view has custom
所以当某个视图上有
actions it's going to tell that
自定义操作时  它就会向用户
to the user and then the user
提示  然后用户就可以用手指
can swipe up or down with their
上下轻扫
finger to cycle through the
随意浏览
current actions of that element.
该元素的当前操作
And when they land on the one
如果用户找到某个元素
that they want to activate a
并且想要激活某个
double tap instead of doing
双击步骤
whatever the default behavior
而不是采用默认行为
will do will initiate that
那样就可以启动
action.
这一类操作
So, for instance, with our
比如说  我们用这个删除
delete we can create a custom
就可以创建一个自定义操作
action called delete, set our
名叫 Delete  并且通过
self as the target with our
deleteCellAction 方法  把我们
delete cell action method that
这个 Self 设为目标
returns a Boolean and that calls
它会返回一个布尔值并调用
the code for actually initiating
代码来
the delete of the cell.
删除这个单元格
On our cell, we're going to
关于这个单元格
override
我们准备覆写
accessibilityCustomActions to
accessibilityCustomActions
contain this custom action.
从而包含这个自定义操作
Now because we're overriding it
现在因为我们
on the cell and the cell itself
要对这个单元格进行覆盖  而它本身
isn't an accessibilityElement,
并不是一个 accessibilityElement
All of its sub elements are
它所有的子元素
going to inherit the custom
都将要继承其父级元素的
actions of its parent.
自定义操作
So, I can actually initiate this
所以  实际上我可以从这个单元格的
delete action from any of the
任何视图中启动这个
views on the cell.
删除的操作
Next, we have the default
接下来  我们要谈谈
activation.
默认激活
So, what if we want to actually
如果我们真的想进行覆盖
override what the default
如果有 VoiceOver 用户
behavior is when a VoiceOver
双击某个元素
user double taps on an element.
那么这里的默认行为是什么
And that's what we're going to
这就是我们准备用来
use to fix the problem of
解决问题的方法  看看如何
actually changing our settings.
真正改变我们的设置
What you can do is override
你可以做的是重写
accessibilityActivate, which
accessibilityActivate
returns a Boolean indicating
它会返回一个布尔值
whether or not the activation
表示是否已经
was successful.
成功激活
So, for example with our switch
再举例说  我们用 Switch 单元格
cells we can override
就可以重写
accessibilityActivate and set
accessibilityActivate
whether or not the switch is on
并根据 Switch 的当前值
based on its current on value.
来设定这个切换键是否打开
And we're always going to return
我们的返回值总是 True
true because we know that that
因为我们知道
action is always going to be
这个操作
successful.
总是会成功
Next, we have adjustable
接下来是可调整元素
elements, so our star rating is
我们的星级评分是可调整的
adjustable and VoiceOver has a
VoiceOver 有一个
mechanism for adjustable
专为可调整元素而设的机制
elements to respond to increment
它根据增加和减少的调用
and decrement calls.
进行调节
So, the first thing we want to
所以  在这个元素的特性里
return in that element's traits
我们首先要返回的
that it is an adjustable element
是一个可调整元素
and that tells VoiceOver that
这就是在告诉 VoiceOver
element is going to respond to
该元素将要响应
the accessibilityIncrement and
accessibilityIncrement 和
decrement calls which we can
accessibilityDdecrement 的调用
override to do whatever behavior
我们可以对它们进行覆写  这样就可以
we need when we increment and
在增加和减少时  完成一切必要的
decrement.
行为
And a user adjusts an adjustable
用户可以通过
element by swiping up and down
手指上下轻扫来
with their finger.
调整可调整元素
Up as an increment, down as a
向上轻扫是增加
decrement.
向下轻扫是减少
So, with our star's view we have
所以在“星级视图”里
the number of stars that
我们有评星的数量
whenever it's set has code that
只要它被设置过  就会产生代码
actually adjusts the view
可以实际调整
itself.
视图
In its traits, we're going to
在它的特性里  我们准备
include the adjustable trait.
加入可调整特性
And in increment we're simply
而在增加函数里
going to increase the number of
我们只需要设定为逐个加星
stars by one and in decrement
而在减少函数里
we're going to decrease the
我们准备采取
number of stars by one and now
逐个减星的办法
that element is fully accessible
这样该元素就对我们的
to our VoiceOver users.
VoiceOver 用户完全开放了
Now I'd like to look at a
现在  我想看看
different problem that we didn't
在样本 App 里还没有出现的
see in our sample app.
另一个问题
So, VoiceOver has this concept
VoiceOver 有这种
of pass-through which happens
pass-through 的概念
when a VoiceOver user double
当 VoiceOver 用户手指双击后
taps and holds their finger and
把手指停在屏幕上
it passes through the panning
就会开启连续追拍手势
gesture so I can actually run my
然后我的手指就可以
finger across the screen and get
在屏幕上滑动  让幻灯片
a more fine adjustment of a
获得更精细的调整
slider like you see in this
就像大家在这张照片页面上
photo's page here.
看到的那样
But we want a way to tell
但是我们希望能找到一种方式
VoiceOver where it should
告诉 VoiceOver
actually focus that panning when
在我启动以后  它应该
I initiate it because if I'm a
把那个追拍聚焦点放在哪里
VoiceOver user then I probably
因为如果我是 VoiceOver 用户
am not going to be able to
我很可能无法准确地
accurately land my finger on
把手指放置在
that little sliding nub in the
右边的那小滑块上
center right, I don't actually
实际上我并不知道
know where it is.
它在哪里
So, we're going to use
所以  我们要使用
accessibilityActivationPoint
accessibilityActivationPoint
which is the point that tells
它的作用是  当 pass-through 情况发生时
VoiceOver when a pass-through
把信息发馈给 VoiceOver
occurs, what part of the UI do
以及用户界面的哪部分内容
you actually want to hook into.
是你真正想要勾入的
So, for instance, if we have our
举个例子  我们有
slider view where we have some
“幻灯视图”这个类
sort of slider nub then we can
里面有某种样式的幻灯滑块
override
这样我们就可以覆写
accessibilityActivationPoint to
accessibilityActivationPoint
be the center of that nub so
把它的值改为滑块中央
that whenever the user passes
这样只要用户直接运用这个
through that gesture it will
手势  它就可以
hook into the center of the nub
勾入滑块中央
and start sliding there.
然后开始滑动
Next, we have custom scrolling,
接下来是自定义滑动方式
so you may have views that have
大家可以有一些带有
swipe gestures on them that you
轻扫手势的视图  并且可以用它们
can use to get to different
进入用户界面的
parts of the UI.
不同位置
For instance, in photos if I
例如  在照片选项里
swipe up then I get to my
如果我往上轻扫  就可以看到照片
details.
细节
And there's a way that we can
现在我们有一种办法
get this behavior for VoiceOver
可以为 VoiceOver 用户
users as well.
提供同样的行为
It's called an
它的名称是
accessibilityScroll, it's
accessibilityScroll
initiated by scrolling with
当 VoiceOver 功能开启时
three fingers when VoiceOver is
它可以通过三根手指的滑动
on.
来触发
And it returns a Boolean to
它将返回一个布尔值
indicate whether or not the
以此来显示
scroll was successful.
滚动是否成功
And it passes through a
它要通过某个
direction so that you can change
方向完成  因此你可以根据
the behavior based on what
用户滚动的具体方向
direction the user is scrolling.
来改变应提供的行为
So, for example with our image
所以  举例来说  我们有了这个画面视图后
view if we wanted to show
如果想要显示
details like we do in the Photos
细节  就像我们在那个照片 App 里所做的那样
app we'd have some property that
我们就需要有某种属性来
tells us whether or not we can
告诉我们  当前能否
currently show the details and
展示这些细节
we have code that actually goes
这里有个代码  它其实是
through and shows those details.
要通过运行并展示这些细节
And so, what we're going to do
接下来我们就要
is override accessibilityScroll,
覆写 accessibilityScroll
we're going to check can we show
接着再检查我们能否展示
our details and are we scrolling
我们这些细节  以及我们翻看滚动的
in the right position or
位置和方向
direction.
是否正确
And if we do we're going to show
如果这样做了  接下来将会显示
our details and return true,
我们的详细信息  并且返回 True
otherwise we're going to return
否则它就会返回
false.
False
And when I return false
当我返回False时
VoiceOver is going to make a
VoiceOver 会发出咣当一声
bonking noise to indicate to the
用来提醒用户
user that whatever swipe that
不管他们刚才使用了
they just did was not a valid
怎样的轻扫动作  都是
swipe.
无效的
Now I'm not going to go through
现在我并不真想打算
actually adding all those things
这样来一遍  把所有东西都
into our sample app, but they
添加到我们的样本 App 里面  但是它们
are in the finished version of
已经被加入到样本 App 的
the sample which you can find
最终版本里了  你们可以
and download at this URL.
在这个 URL 去查看并下载
And I recommend that you go and
我推荐大家去
check it out and see how that
看看该例子代码
code is implemented and see how
是如何执行
it works in action, play around
如何运行启动  并且亲身测试
with it yourself.
使用一番
Instead, I'd like to spend a
至于现在  我想稍微
little bit of time talking about
花点时间来介绍
Drag-and-Drop.
拖放功能
So, for those of you that missed
对于先前错过了
it at the keynote we unveiled
我们发布的 Keynote 的人
Drag-and-Drop finally coming to
现在的 iOS 系统里终于推出了拖放功能
iOS where I can drag pieces of
我可以拖动一条条的内容
content and drop it in other
把它放置到
places in the interface.
界面的其他位置
For instance, if I have photos
举个例子  如果我在打开备忘录
open next to notes I can drag a
以后又打开照片  那么就可以拖拽
photo and drop it into one of my
一张照片  将它放到我的一则备忘录
notes.
笔记里
Now because this was just
由于这项功能在
unveiled two days ago I don't
两天前刚刚发布
really expect all of you to
所以我不能指望所有人
already understand how that API
都已经理解这个 API 是如何
works.
运行的
But there are just two key
不过这里有两个关键
concepts that you need to
概念  是需要大家
understand before I talk about
在我介绍这项辅助功能之前
the accessibility and that's
就应该知道的  那就是
drag sources and drop points.
拖曳源和放置点
So, drag sources are all the
拖曳源是在我的视图里
points on my view that I can
启动拖曳
initiate a drag from and drop
所有单点的集合
points conversely are all the
而放置点则相反  它是我视图里
places on my view that I can
所有可以放置内容的
drop content.
位置
So, for instance, on the Home
比如  在主屏幕上
screen which now uses
现在我使用拖放功能
Drag-and-Drop for rearranging
来重新布置图标
icons I have three drop points
当我在移动某个 App 图标时
for each app when I'm moving
给其他每个 App 周围留了三个
another.
放置点
The first is the left drop point
第一个是左放置点
which allows me to drop the app
它让我能够把正在拖移的
I'm currently moving to the left
App 放到左侧
and shift everything else to the
同时把其他所有东西都移动到
right.
右侧
I have the center drop point
我的这个中间放置点
that will create a folder
可以在两个 App 之间
between the two apps.
创建一个文件夹
And I have the right drop point
然后我还有这个右放置点
that will drop my current app to
可以把当前 App 拖放到
the right.
右侧
And we need a way of describing
我们需要一种方式
those different drag sources and
来向 VioceOver 用户描述
drop points to our VoiceOver
这些不同的拖曳源和
users.
放置点
And to do that we're going to
为此我们将要
use this new API
使用这个全新的 API
accessibilityDrag
accessibilityDrag
SourcesDescriptors and
SourcesDescriptors
accessibilityDrop
还有 accessibilityDrop
PointDescriptors.
PointDescriptors
They're arrays of
它们都是 UIAccessibility
UIAccessibility
LocationDescriptor 里面
LocationDescriptor that
的数组
described the drags and the
用来描述拖曳和放置
drops for review.
以供审阅
So, we create a UIAccessibility
因此  我们给每个拖放操作
LocationDescriptor for each
都创建了 UIAccessibility
drag-and-drop.
LocationDescriptor
The view is going to be the view
这里的 View
that has the drag or drop
是要与拖放交互
interaction associated with it.
相关联的视图
The point is the point where the
Point 是拖曳的起始位置
drag is initiated from or the
或者是与放置
drop is associated with.
相关联的位置
And the name is meant to
Name 是用来描述
describe what that drag or drop
拖曳放置的具体操作
does.
内容
And there's even an attributed
这里还有一个属性名称
name where you can use all those
通过它  你可以使用
attributed keys that I was
我先前提到的所有属性键
referring to earlier to tweak
并且用来调整
the way that VoiceOver describes
VoiceOver 用来记录
the name of the descriptor.
描述符名称的方法
So, let's take a look at how
那么  让我们来看看
this works in code.
这是如何在代码中实现的
Now this is just a hypothetical
这只是一个假设的例子
example this isn't an actually
并非一个真正的
springboard code.
Springboard 代码
But let's say that I was
不过可以假设一下
implementing rearranging apps
我正在执行重新排布 App 的任务
and I have a method that returns
并且有一个方法  可以把
an app view for a given index
App 视图值返回到
path.
给定的索引路径
Well I'm going to start by
好的  我准备着手
initializing that app view and
把这个 App 视图实现初始化
then I'm going to create a drag
然后创建一个拖曳描述符
descriptor and I'm going to give
我要把它命名为 Drag xxx
it the name drag whatever the
App 名称
app name is because that's what
因为我要做的就是
I'm doing.
这个事情
And then the center of where the
接下来 是 App 被拖曳时的中心位置
app is dragged from or sorry the
抱歉说错了  是 App 被拖曳时
point where the app is dragged
这个拖曳点是处于
from is its center.
中心位置
And the view that actually has
实际形成拖曳交互的视图
that drag interaction is myself.
是用我自己的图片
Then I'm going to override the
然后我将覆写
app view's drag source
App 视图的拖曳源描述器
descriptors to include that new
以便把新的拖曳描述器
drag descriptor.
包括进来
Now let's look at the drops.
现在让我们看看关于放置的代码
So, first of all, we need to
首先  我们需要
identify the points on my app
在我的 App 视图上确定所有的点
view where I actually want to
它们将是我确实是要
use the drop, the left and the
用来放置的地方  左边的点
right point, I know where the
右边的点  我已经知道
center is already.
中心点在哪里
And I'm going to create a
我准备为每一个点
descriptor for each of those.
都创建一个描述符
My leftDescriptor I'm going to
关于我的 leftDescriptor  我准备说
say drop left of blank,
拖放到左边空白处
folderDescriptor I'm going to
关于 folderDescriptor
say create a folder with the app
我准备说  创建包含该 App 的文件夹
and the rightDescriptor drop
还有 rightDescriptor
right of the app.
就拖放到这个 App 的右边
And then I'm going to override
接下来  我将覆写
accessibilityDrop
accessibilityDrop
PointDescriptors to include all
PointDescriptors  把这些新的描述符
those new descriptors and I'll
都包括进来  然后我将
return my app view.
返回我的 App 视图
And that's it, pretty simple.
就是这样  十分简单
But important to convey for the
然而对于 VoiceOver 用户来说
VoiceOver user what each of your
告诉他们  你的每一次拖放功能交互是
Drag-and-Drop interactions are
怎样一种情况
like.
十分重要
So, if you're going to implement
如果你准备执行这个功能
this feature then please take
那么请花一点时间
the time to do the accessibility
也试一下对应的
for it as well.
VoiceOver 辅助功能
Now I talked about a lot of
今天我讲了很多东西
stuff today, we looked at some
我们了解了一些新特性
new features, we looked at
我们了解怎样
auditing your own app for
检查自己的 App 里的
accessibility, and we looked at
辅助功能
various portions of our API to
我们还了解到我们这个 API 的不同部分
solve the problems that you find
以便解决大家在检查过程中
while auditing.
发现的问题
And that's all great technical
这些都是非常伟大的科技成果
stuff, but I want to bring it
但是我想回到开头的话题
back to the beginning to remind
我想提醒一下
you why we're all actually in
我们相聚在这个房间里的
this room.
真正目的
Accessibility is about people,
辅助功能是为了人而设计的
the common person's life is
在科技的帮助下
enhanced by technology, but for
普通人的生活可以得以改善
people with disabilities it's
但对于残障人士来说
transformative.
这可是根本性的改变
Accessible technology enables
辅助技术让人们能够
people to live their lives the
根据自己的意愿
way that they want to, to
过自己想过的生活
accomplish goals and tasks that
完成以前难以企及的目标和任务
were once unattainable, to have
得到以往在社会群体里
jobs and roles in their
无法拥有的
communities that they couldn't
工作和角色
have had before, and to interact
并且用一种
with the world in ways that were
前所未有的方式
once impossible.
与世界互动
The work that you do to ensure
你现在所做的工作
that your apps work for everyone
确保了你的 App 能够为每个人所用
is critical.
这一点非常关键
So, we thank you for the amazing
所以  我们在此由衷感谢
work that you've already done,
你们已完成的杰出成绩
that you will continue to do,
你们将继续的事业
and that you will start today as
你们今天即将开始的工作
we work together to make Apple's
因为我们将并肩协作
platforms more inclusive.
让 Apple 平台更具包容性
Now for more information, you
如果你们想了解更多信息 可以
can go to this URL where we've
访问这个 URL 这里有我们
collected some URLs that are
收集的一些有用的 URL
helpful for you like some
比如说  某些开发者的
developer documentation, as well
文档纪录  以及我们的
as our accessibility website.
辅助功能网站等
And there are a couple of
另外  还有一些
related sessions, there are the
相关议程  包括我前面提到的
three sessions related to
与 Dynamic Type 相关的三个议程
dynamic type that I covered
除此之外  还会有一个关于
before, and there's a media and
媒体与游戏辅助功能的演讲
gaming accessibility talk
它专门针对与媒体和游戏有关的 App
specifically for apps related to
这场演讲
media and gaming that's in this
就紧接在我的演讲过后
room right after I'm done.
就在这个房间
Thank you very much, have a
非常感谢诸位的到来
great rest of your conference.
希望大家接下来能够在这次大会上度过美好的时光